Drink up, me hearties, yo ho
We kidnap and ravage and don't give a hoot
Yo ho, yo ho
A pirate's life for me
We extort, we pilfer, we filch and sack
Drink up
Quiet, missy.
Cursed pirates sail these waters.
You don't want to bring them.
Mr. Gibbs, that will do.
She was singing about pirates.
It's bad luck to be singing about pirates
with us mired in this unnatural fog.
Mark my words.
Consider them marked.
On your way.
Aye, Lieutenant.
It's bad luck to have a woman on board, too.
Even a miniature one.
I think it'd be rather exciting to meet a pirate.
Think again, Miss Swann.
Vile and dissolute creatures, the lot of them.
I intend that any man who sails under a pirate flag
or wears a pirate brand gets what he deserves.
A short drop and a sudden stop.
Lieutenant Norrington, I appreciate your fervor,
but I'm concerned about the effect
this subject will have upon my daughter.
My apologies, Governor Swann.
Actually, I find it all fascinating.
Yes. That's what concerns me.
Look! A boy! There's a boy in the water!
Man overboard!
Man the ropes. Fetch a hook.
Haul him aboard.
He's still breathing.
Mary, Mother of God.
What happened here?
It's the powder magazine.
Merchant vessels run heavily armed.
A lot of good it did them.
Everyone's thinking it. I'm just saying it.
Pirates.
There's no proof of that. It's probably an accident.
Rouse the captain immediately.
Heave to and take in sail. Launch the boats.
Elizabeth, I want you to accompany the boy.
He'll be in your charge.
Take care of him.
It's okay.
My name's Elizabeth Swann.
Will Turner.
I'm watching over you, Will.
You're a pirate.
Has he said anything?
His name's William Turner. That's all I found out.
Take him below.
Elizabeth?
Are you all right?
Are you decent?
Yes.
Still abed at this hour?
Oh, it's a beautiful day.
I have a gift for you.
Oh, it's beautiful.
lsn't it?
May I inquire as to the occasion?
Does a father need an occasion to dote upon his daughter?
Go on.
Actually, I...
I hoped you might wear it for the ceremony today.
The ceremony?
Captain Norrington's promotion ceremony.
I knew it.
Commodore Norrington, as he's about to become.
A fine gentleman, don't you think?
He fancies you, you know.
Elizabeth? How's it coming?
It's difficult to say.
I'm told it's the latest fashion in London.
Well, women in London must've learnt not to breathe.
Milord, you have a visitor.
Mr. Turner.
Good to see you again.
Good day, sir.
I have your order.
Well.
The blade is folded steel.
That's gold filigree laid into the handle.
If I may.
Perfectly balanced.
The tang is nearly the full width of the blade.
lmpressive. Very impressive.
Now, now.
Commodore Norrington is going to be very pleased with this.
Do pass my compliments on to your master.
I shall.
A craftsman is always pleased to hear his work is appreciated.
Elizabeth, you look absolutely stunning.
Will.
It's so good to see you.
I had a dream about you last night.
About me?
Yes, is that entirely proper for you --
About the day we met. Do you remember?
How could I forget, Miss Swann?
How many times must I ask you to call me Elizabeth?
At least once more, Miss Swann, as always.
There. See?
At least the boy has a sense of propriety.
We really must be going. There you are.
Good day, Mr. Turner.
Come along.
Good day.
Elizabeth.
What -- hey.
Hold up, there, you.
It's a shilling to tie up your boat at the dock.
And I shall need to know your name.
What do you say to three shillings,
and we forget the name?
Welcome to Port Royal, Mr. Smith.
Two paces march!
Right about-face!
Present arms!
This dock is off limits to civilians.
I'm terribly sorry. I didn't know.
If I see one, I shall inform you immediately.
There's some sort of high-toned and fancy to-do up at the fort.
How could it be two upstanding gentlemen such as yourselves
did not merit an invitation?
Someone has to make sure this dock stays off limits.
It's a fine goal, to be sure.
But it seems to me that a ship like that
makes this one here a bit superfluous, really.
The Dauntless is the power in these waters, true.
But there's no ship as can match the Interceptor for speed.
I've heard of one.
It's supposed to be very fast. Nigh uncatchable.
The Black Pearl,
Well, there's no real ship as can match the Interceptor,
Black Pearl is a real ship.
No. No, it's not.
Yes, it is. I've seen it.
You've seen it?
Yes.
You haven't seen it.
Yes, I have.
You've seen a ship with black sails
that's crewed by the damned and captained by a man so evil
that Hell itself spat him back out?
No.
But I have seen a ship with black sails.
Oh.
No ship that's not crewed by the damned
and captained by a man so evil that Hell spat him out
could possibly have black sails, therefore couldn't be
any other ship than the Black Pearl,
Is that what you're saying?
No.
Like I said, there's no real ship
as can match the Interceptor,
Hey!
You!
Get away from there!
You don't have permission to be there.
I'm sorry. It's such a pretty boat.
Ship.
What's your name?
Smith. Or Smithy, if you like.
What's your purpose in Port Royal, Mr. Smith?
Yeah. And no lies.
Well, then, I confess.
It is my intention to commandeer one of these ships,
pick up a crew in Tortuga, raid, pillage, plunder,
and otherwise pilfer my weaselly black guts out.
-I said no lies. -I think he's telling the truth.
If he were telling the truth, he wouldn't have told us.
Unless you wouldn't believe the truth even if he told you.
May I have a moment?
You look lovely, Elizabeth.
I apologize if I seem forward, but I must speak my mind.
This promotion throws into sharp relief
that which I have not yet achieved.
A marriage to a fine woman.
You have become a fine woman, Elizabeth.
I can't breathe.
Yes, I'm a bit nervous myself.
And then they made me their chief.
Elizabeth?
Elizabeth!
My God.
The rocks!
Sir, it's a miracle she missed them.
-Will you be saving her? -I can't swim.
Pride of the King's Navy, you are.
Do not lose these.
What was that?
Make way!
I got her!
She's not breathing!
Move!
I never would've thought of that.
Clearly you've never been to Singapore.
Where did you get that?
On your feet.
Elizabeth!
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Shoot him.
-Father. -What?
Commodore, do you really intend to kill my rescuer?
I believe thanks are in order.
Had a brush with the East lndia Trading Company, did we, pirate?
Hang him.
Keep your guns on him, men. Gillette, fetch some irons.
Well, well.
Jack Sparrow, isn't it?
Captain Jack Sparrow, if you please, sir.
Well, I don't see your ship, Captain.
I'm in the market, as it were.
He said he'd come to commandeer one.
Told you he was telling the truth. These are his, sir.
No additional shot nor powder.
A compass that doesn't point North.
And I half expected it to be made of wood.
You are without doubt the worst pirate I've ever heard of.
But you have heard of me.
Commodore, I really must protest.
Carefully, Lieutenant.
Pirate or not, this man saved my life.
One good deed is not enough to redeem a man
Though it seems enough to condemn him.
lndeed.
Finally.
No.
No! Don't shoot!
I knew you'd warm up to me.
Commodore Norrington, my effects, please.
And my hat.
Commodore.
-lt is Elizabeth, isn't it? -It's Miss Swann.
Miss Swann, if you'd be so kind.
Come, come, dear. We don't have all day.
Now if you'll be very kind.
Easy on the goods, darling.
You're despicable.
Sticks and stones, love.
I saved your life. You save mine. We're square.
Gentlemen, milady, you will always remember this
as the day that you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow.
Whoa!
Now will you shoot him?
Open fire!
Hey!
On his heels!
Take cover, man!
Gillette, Mr. Sparrow has a dawn appointment with the gallows.
I would hate for him to miss it.
Search upstairs!
Look lively, men!
Whoa!
Right where I left you.
Not where I left you.
You're the one they're hunting.
The pirate.
You seem familiar. Have I threatened you before?
I make a point of avoiding familiarity with pirates.
It would be a shame to put a mark on your record.
So if you'll excuse me.
Do you think this wise, boy?
Crossing blades with a pirate?
You threatened Miss Swann.
Only a little.
You know what you're doing. I'll give you that. Excellent form.
But how's your footwork?
If I step here.
Very good.
And now I step again.
Ta.
That is a wonderful trick.
Except, once again, you are between me and my way out.
And now you have no weapon.
Who makes all these?
I do.
And I practice with them three hours a day.
You need to find yourself a girl, mate.
Or perhaps the reason you practice three hours a day
is that you found one
and are otherwise incapable of wooing said strumpet.
You're not a eunuch, are you?
I practice three hours a day so when I meet a pirate,
I can kill it!
You cheated.
Pirate.
Move away.
No.
-Please move. -No.
I cannot just step aside and let you escape.
This shot is not meant for you.
There he is! Over here!
Excellent work, Mr. Brown.
You've assisted in the capture of a fugitive.
Just doing my civic duty, sir.
I trust you will remember this is the day
Captain Jack Sparrow almost escaped.
Take him away.
-Can you smell it? -Come here.
-It's marrowbone. -Come here.
-Want a juicy bone? -Come here.
-Come here, boy! -Come on.
You can keep doing that forever. The dog is never going to move.
Oh, excuse us
if we haven't resigned ourself to the gallows just yet.
There you go, miss.
It was a difficult day for you, I'm sure.
I suspected Commodore Norrington would propose.
I must admit, I wasn't prepared for it.
I meant you being threatened by that pirate. Sounds terrifying.
Oh.
Yes, it was terrifying.
But the commodore proposed. Fancy that.
Now, that's a smart match, miss, if it's not too bold to say.
It is a smart match.
He's a fine man.
He's what any woman should dream of marrying.
Well, that Will Turner. He's a fine man, too.
That is too bold.
Well, begging your pardon, miss. It was not my place.
Has my daughter given you an answer yet?
No, she hasn't.
Well, she has had a very trying day.
Ghastly weather, don't you think?
Bleak. Very bleak.
What's that?
Cannon fire!
Return fire!
-I know those guns. -Men to arms!
It's the Pearl,
The Black Pearl?
I've heard stories.
She's been preying on ships and settlements for near 10 years.
Never leaves any survivors.
No survivors?
Then where do the stories come from, I wonder?
Coming through!
Aaah!
Sight the muzzle flash!
Aim for the flashes!
I need a full strike, fore and aft.
Mr. Stephens, more cartridges!
Governor, barricade yourself in my office.
That's an order.
Don't!
Hello, chum.
Up there.
Miss Swann, they've come to kidnap you!
What?
You're the governor's daughter.
In here!
Listen. They haven't seen you.
The first chance you get, run to the fort.
Gotcha.
No! No! No! It's hot!
You burned me!
Come on!
No!
We know you're here, poppet.
Poppet.
Come out and we promise we won't hurt you.
Eh?
We will find you, poppet.
You've got something of ours, and it calls to us.
The gold calls to us.
Gold.
Hello, poppet.
Parley.
What?
I invoke the right of parley.
According to the Code of the Brethren set down by the pirates Morgan and Bartholomew,
you have to take me to your captain.
I know the Code.
If an adversary demands parley,
you can do them no harm until the parley is complete.
To blazes with the Code.
She wants to be taken to the captain.
And she'll go without a fuss.
We must honor the Code.
Say goodbye.
Goodbye.
-Will! -Come on!
Elizabeth.
Out of my way, scum!
My sympathies, friend.
You've no manner of luck at all.
Come on, doggy.
It's just you and me now.
It's you and old Jack. Come on.
Come on. That's a boy.
Good boy. Come get the bone.
That's a good boy. Come on.
A bit closer. A bit closer.
That's it. That's it, doggy.
Come on, you filthy, slimy, mangy cur.
-Don't do that.
No, no! I didn't mean it!
I didn't.
This ain't the armory.
Well, well, well. Look what we have here, Twigg.
Captain Jack Sparrow.
Last time I saw you,
you were all alone on a godforsaken island,
shrinking into the distance.
His fortunes aren't improved much.
Worry about your own fortunes, gentlemen.
The deepest circle of hell is reserved for betrayers and mutineers.
So there is a curse.
That's interesting.
You know nothing of hell.
That's very interesting.
I didn't know we was taking on captives.
She's invoked the right of parley with Captain Barbossa.
-I'm here to -- -You'll speak when spoken to.
And ye will not lay a hand
on those under the protection of parley.
Aye, sir.
My apologies, miss.
Captain Barbossa, I am here to negotiate
the cessation of hostilities against Port Royal.
There were a lot of long words in there.
We're naught but humble pirates.
What is it that you want?
I want you to leave and never come back.
I'm disinclined to acquiesce to your request.
Means "no."
Very well.
I'll drop it.
Me holds are bursting with swag.
That bit of shine matters to us?
Why?
It's what you've been searching for. I recognize this ship.
I saw it eight years ago on the crossing from England.
Did you, now?
Fine.
I suppose if it is worthless,
there's no point in me keeping it.
You have a name, missy?
Elizabeth Turner.
I'm a maid in the governor's household.
Miss Turner.
Bootstrap.
How does a maid own a trinket such as that?
Family heirloom, perhaps?
I didn't steal it, if that's what you mean.
Very well. Hand it over.
We'll put your town to our rudder and ne'er return.
Our bargain?
Still the guns and stow them.
Wait! You have to take me to shore!
According to the Code --
First, your return to shore was not part of our agreement.
So I must do nothing.
You must be a pirate for the Pirate's Code to apply,
and you're not.
Thirdly, the Code is more what you'd call guidelines
than actual rules.
Welcome aboard the Black Pearl, Miss Turner.
They've taken her. They've taken Elizabeth.
Mr. Murtogg, remove this man.
We have to hunt them down. We must save her.
And where do you propose we start?
If you have information concerning my daughter,
please share it.
That Jack Sparrow. He talked about the Black Pearl,
Mentioned it is more what he did.
Ask him where it is. He could lead us to it.
No. The pirates who invaded this fort
left Sparrow locked in his cell, ergo they are not his allies.
We will establish their most likely course.
That's not good enough!
Mr. Turner, you are not a military man.
You are not a sailor.
You are a blacksmith.
And this is not the moment for rash actions.
Do not make the mistake of thinking
you are the only man here who cares for Elizabeth.
You. Sparrow.
You are familiar with that ship. The Black Pearl,
I've heard of it.
Where does it make berth?
Have you not heard the stories?
Captain Barbossa and his crew of miscreants
sail from the dreaded lsla de Muerta.
It's an island that cannot be found,
except by those who already know where it is.
The ship's real enough.
lts anchorage must be a real place.
Where is it?
Why ask me?
Because you're a pirate.
And you want to turn pirate yourself, is that it?
Never.
They took Miss Swann.
Oh, so it is that you found a girl.
I see. Well, if you're intending to brave all,
hasten to her rescue, and so win fair lady's heart,
you'll have to do it alone, mate.
I see no profit in it for me.
I can get you out of here.
How's that? They key's run off.
I helped build these cells.
These are half-pin barrel hinges.
With the right leverage and the proper application of strength.
The door will lift free.
What's your name?
Will Turner.
That would be short for William, I imagine.
Good, strong name.
No doubt named for your father.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Well, Mr. Turner, I've changed me mind.
If you spring me from this cell, I swear on pain of death
I shall take you to the Black Pearl
and your bonny lass.
Do we have an accord?
Agreed.
Get me out.
Hurry. Someone will have heard that.
Not without my effects.
We're going to steal the ship?
That ship?
Commandeer.
We're going to commandeer that ship.
Nautical term.
One question about your business.
Or there's no use going.
This girl.
How far are you willing to go to save her?
I'd die for her.
Oh, good.
No worries, then.
This is either madness or brilliance.
It's remarkable how often those two traits coincide.
Everyone stay calm! We are taking over the ship.
Aye! Avast!
This ship cannot be crewed by two men.
You'll never make it out of the bay.
Son, I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
Savvy?
Commodore.
LT. GlLLETTE: Sir, they've taken the Dauntless!
Commodore!
They've taken the ship!
Sparrow and Turner have taken the Dauntless!
Rash, Turner. Too rash.
That is without doubt the worst pirate I have ever seen.
Here they come.
Bring her around! Bring her around!
Search every cabin, every hull, down to the bilges.
Sailors, back to the Interceptor,
Now!
Thank you, Commodore, for getting us ready to make way.
We'd have had a hard time of it by ourselves.
Set topsails and clear up this mess.
With the wind, we won't catch them.
I don't need to. Get them in range of the long nines.
Hands, come about!
Run out the guns!
We are to fire on our own ship, sir?
I'd rather see her at the bottom of the ocean
than in the hands of a pirate.
Commodore, he's disabled the rudder chain, sir.
Abandon ship!
That's got to be the best pirate I've ever seen.
So it would seem.
WlLL: When I was a lad living in England,
my mother raised me by herself.
After she died, I came out here, looking for my father.
Is that so?
My father, Will Turner.
It was only after you learnt my name you agreed to help.
Since that's what I wanted, I didn't press the matter.
I'm not a simpleton, Jack.
You knew my father.
I knew him.
Probably one of the few who knew him as William Turner.
Everyone else called him Bootstrap or Bootstrap Bill.
Bootstrap?
Good man. Good pirate.
I swear, you look just like him.
It's not true.
He was a merchant sailor.
A respectable man who obeyed the law.
He was a bloody pirate. A scallywag.
My father was not a pirate.
Put it away, son. It's not worth you getting beat again.
You ignored the rules of engagement.
In a fair fight, I'd kill you.
Then that's not much incentive for me to fight fair.
Now, as long as you're just hanging there, pay attention.
The only rules that really matter are these.
What a man can do and what a man can't do.
For instance,
you can accept that your father was a pirate and a good man
or you can't.
Pirate is in your blood,
so you'll have to square with that someday.
Now, me, for example.
I can let you drown.
But I can't bring this ship into Tortuga
all by me onesy, savvy?
So.
Can you sail under the command of a pirate?
Or can you not?
Tortuga?
Tortuga.
More importantly, it is indeed a sad life
that has never breathed deep this sweet bouquet
that is Tortuga, savvy?
What do you think?
lt'll linger.
I'll tell you, mate,
if every town in the world were like this one,
no man would ever feel unwanted.
Scarlett!
Not sure I deserved that.
Giselle!
Who was she?
What?
I may have deserved that.
Curse you for breathing, you slack-jawed idiot!
Mother's love!
Jack!
You should know better than to wake a man when he's sleeping.
It's bad luck.
Fortunately, I know how to counter it.
The man who did the waking
buys the man who was sleeping a drink.
The man who was sleeping drinks while listening to a proposition
from the man who did the waking.
Aye, that'll about do it.
Blast! I'm already awake!
That was for the smell.
Keep a sharp eye.
Now, what's the nature of this venture of yourn?
I'm going after the Black Pearl,
I know where it's going to be, and I'm gonna take it.
Jack, it's a fool's errand.
You know better than me the tales of the Black Pearl,
That's why I know what Barbossa is up to.
All I need is a crew.
From what I hear of Barbossa,
he's not a man to suffer fools, nor strike a bargain with one.
I'd say it's a good thing I'm not a fool.
Prove me wrong.
What makes you think Barbossa will give up his ship to you?
Let's just say it's a matter of leverage.
The kid?
That is the child of Bootstrap Bill Turner.
His only child, savvy?
Is he, now?
"Leverage," says you.
"I think I feel a change in the wind," says i.
I'll find us a crew.
There's bound to be some sailors crazy as you.
One can only hope.
Take what you can.
Give nothing back.
You'll be dining with the captain.
And he requests you wear this.
You tell the captain
that I am disinclined to acquiesce to his request.
He said you'd say that.
He also said, if that be the case,
you'll be dining with the crew.
And you'll be naked.
Fine.
There's no need to stand on ceremony, nor call to impress.
You must be hungry.
Try the wine.
And the apples.
One of those next?
It's poisoned.
There would be no sense to be killing you.
Release me. You have your trinket.
I'm of no further value to you.
You don't know what this is, do you?
It's a pirate medallion.
This is Aztec gold.
One of 882 identical pieces
they delivered in a stone chest to Cortes himself.
Blood money paid to stem the slaughter
he wreaked upon them with his armies.
But the greed of Cortes was insatiable.
So the heathen gods placed upon the gold a terrible curse.
Any mortal that removes
but a single piece from that stone chest
shall be punished for eternity.
I hardly believe in ghost stories anymore, Captain.
Aye.
That's exactly what I thought when we were told the tale.
Buried on an island of dead what cannot be found,
except for those who know where it is.
Find it, we did.
There be the chest.
lnside be the gold.
And we took them all.
We spent them and traded them
and frittered them away on drink and food
and pleasurable company.
The more we gave them away, the more we came to realize,
the drink would not satisfy,
food turned to ash in our mouths,
and all the pleasurable company in the world
could not slake our lust.
We are cursed men, Miss Turner.
Compelled by greed, we were, but now we are consumed by it.
There is one way we can end our curse.
All the scattered pieces of the Aztec gold
must be restored and the blood repaid.
Thanks to ye, we have the final piece.
And the blood to be repaid?
That's why there's no sense to be killin' you yet.
Apple?
Arr!
No!
I'm curious.
After killing me, what is it you're planning on doing next?
Aah!
Aaaah!
Look!
The moonlight shows us for what we really are.
We are not among the living, and so we cannot die.
But neither are we dead.
For too long I've been parched and unable to quench it.
Too long I've been starving to death and haven't died.
I feel nothing.
Not the wind on my face nor the spray of the sea
nor the warmth of a woman's flesh.
You best start believing in ghost stories, Miss Turner.
You're in one!
What are you looking at? Back to work!
Feast your eyes, Captain.
All of them faithful hands before the mast.
Every man worth his salt.
And crazy to boot.
So this is your able-bodied crew?
-You, sailor! -Cotton, sir.
Mr. Cotton, do you have the courage to follow orders
and stay true in the face of danger and death?
Mr. Cotton! Answer, man!
He's a mute. Poor devil had his tongue cut out.
He trained the parrot to talk for him.
No one's yet figured how.
Mr. Cotton's parrot.
Same question.
Wind in the sails! Wind in the sails!
Mostly we figure that means "yes."
Of course it does.
Satisfied?
Well, you've proved they're mad.
And what's the benefit for us?
Anamaria.
I suppose you didn't deserve that.
No, that one I deserved.
You stole my boat!
Actually --
Borrowed. Borrowed without permission.
But with every intention of bringing it back.
But you didn't!
You'll get another one.
I will.
A better one.
A better one!
That one.
What one?
That one?
Aye, that one.
-What say you? -Aye!
Aye!
Anchors aweigh!
No, no, it's frightful bad luck to bring a woman aboard, sir.
lt'll be far worse not to have her.
How can we sail to an island that nobody can find
with a compass that doesn't work?
Aye, the compass doesn't point North,
but we're not trying to find North, are we?
We should drop canvas, sir.
She can hold a bit longer.
What's in your head that's put you in such a fine mood?
We're catching up.
Time to go, poppet.
Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho! Ho!
Dead men tell no tales.
Puts a chill in the bones
how many honest sailors have been claimed by this passage.
How is it that Jack came by that compass?
Not a lot's known about Jack fore he showed up in Tortuga
with a mind to go after the treasure of the lsla de Muerta.
That was before I'd met him.
Back when he was Captain of the Black Pearl,
What?
He failed to mention that.
He plays things closer to the vest now.
And a hard-learned lesson it was.
Three days out, the first mate comes to him
and says everything's an equal share.
That should mean the location of the treasure.
Jack gives up the bearings.
That night, there was a mutiny.
They marooned Jack on an island and left him to die,
but not before he'd gone mad with the heat.
So that's the reason for all the...
Reason's got nothing to do with it.
Now, Will, when a pirate's marooned,
he's a given a pistol with a single shot. One shot.
Well, that won't do much good hunting or to be rescued.
But after three weeks of a starving belly and thirst,
that pistol will start to look real friendly.
But Jack escaped the island, and he still has that single shot.
Oh, he won't use it, though, save on one man.
His mutinous first mate.
-Barbossa. -Aye.
How did Jack get off the island?
Well, I'll tell ye.
He waded out into the shallows.
He waited there three days and three nights
till all manner of sea creatures
'came acclimated to his presence.
And on the fourth morning,
he roped a couple of sea turtles,
lashed them together, and made a raft.
He roped a couple of sea turtles?
Aye, sea turtles.
What did he use for rope?
Human hair.
From my back.
Let go the anchor!
Aye, Captain, aye!
Young Mr. Turner and l are to go ashore.
Captain, what if the worst should happen?
Keep to the Code.
Aye, the Code.
Move.
10 years of hoarding swag.
And now we finally get to spend it.
Once we're quit of the curse, we'll be rich men.
You can buy an eye what actually fits and is made of glass.
This one does splinter something terrible.
Stop rubbing it.
What Code is Gibbs to keep to if the worst should happen?
Pirate's Code.
Any man who falls behind is left behind.
No heroes amongst thieves?
For having such a bleak outlook on pirates,
you're well on your way to becoming one.
Sprung a man from jail,
commandeered a ship of the fleet,
sailed with a buccaneer crew out of Tortuga.
And you're completely obsessed with treasure.
That's not true. I am not obsessed with treasure.
Not all treasure is silver and gold, mate.
Gentlemen, the time has come!.
Our salvation is nigh!
Our torment is near an end.
Elizabeth.
For 10 years we've been tested and tried,
and each man jack of you here
has proved his mettle a hundred times over
and a hundred times again!
Suffered, I have!
Punished, we were, the lot of us.
Disproportionate to our crime!
Here it is!
The cursed treasure of Cortes himself.
Every last piece that went astray, we have returned.
Save for this.
Jack!
Not yet. We wait for the opportune moment.
881 we found, but despaired of ever finding the last.
When's that?
When it's of greatest profit to you?
May I ask you something?
Have I ever given you reason not to trust me?
Do us a favor.
I know it's difficult for you, but please stay here
and try not to do anything stupid.
And who among us has paid the blood sacrifice owed to the heathen gods?
Us!
And whose blood must yet be paid?
Hers!
You know the first thing I'm gonna do
after the curse is lifted?
Eat a whole bushel of apples.
Begun by blood.
By blood undone.
Sorry, Jack. I'm not gonna be your leverage.
That's it?
Waste not.
Did it work?
-I don't feel no different. -How do we tell?
You're not dead.
No.
He shot me!
It didn't work.
The curse it still upon us!
You, maid! Your father, what was his name?
Was your father William Turner?
No.
Where's his child that sailed from England eight years ago?
The child in whose veins flows the blood of William Turner?
You two!
You brought us the wrong person!
No!
She had the medallion. She's the proper age.
She said her name was Turner.
I think she lied to us.
You brought us here for nothing.
I won't take questioning or second guesses from you, Twigg.
Who's to blame?
Every decision you've made has led us from bad to worse.
It was you who sent Bootstrap to the depths!
Yeah!
And it's you who brought us here in the first place.
If any coward here dare challenge me, let him speak!
I say we cut her throat and spill all her blood,
just in case.
Yeah!
The medallion!
She's taken it!
Get after her, you feckless pack of ingrates!
No oars here!
Where's the oars?
The oars have gone missing.
Find them!
Find the oars!
You.
You're supposed to be dead!
Am I not?
Palulay.
Palu-li-la-la-lulu.
Parlili.
Parsnip, parsley, partner, partner.
Parley?
That's the one! Parley!
Parley!
Parley?
Damn to the depths whatever man that thought up "parley"!
That would be the French.
Not more pirates.
Welcome aboard, Miss Elizabeth.
Mr. Gibbs?
Hey, boy, where be Jack?
Jack?
Jack Sparrow?
He fell behind.
Keep to the Code.
Weigh anchor!
Hoist the sails! Make quick!
How the blazes did you get off that island?
When you marooned me on that godforsaken spit of land,
you forgot one very important thing, mate.
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
Well, I won't be making that mistake again.
Gents, you all remember Captain Jack Sparrow?
Aye.
Kill him.
The girl's blood didn't work, did it?
Hold your fire!
You know whose blood we need.
I know whose blood you need.
What sort of a man trades a man's life for a ship?
Pirate.
Here. Let me.
Thank you.
You said you gave Barbossa my name as yours.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm sorry. Blacksmith's hands. I know they're rough.
No. I mean yes, they are, but...
But don't stop.
Elizabeth.
It's yours.
I thought I'd lost it the day they rescued me.
It was a gift from my father.
He sent it to me.
Why did you take it?
Because I was afraid that you were a pirate.
That would have been awful.
It wasn't your blood they needed.
It was my father's blood.
My blood.
The blood of a pirate.
Will, I'm so sorry. Please forgive me.
You expect to leave me on some beach
with nothing but a name and your word it's the one I need
and watch you sail away in my ship?
No.
I expect to leave you standing on some beach
with absolutely no name at all,
watching me sail away on my ship,
and then I'll shout the name back to you.
Savvy?
That still leaves the problem of me on some beach
with naught but a name and your word
it's the one I need.
Of the two of us,
I'm the only one who hasn't committed mutiny.
Therefore, my word is the one we'll be trusting.
Although, I suppose I should be thanking you because, in fact,
if you hadn't betrayed me and left me to die,
I would have an equal share in that curse, same as you.
Funny old world, isn't it?
Captain, we're coming up on the Interceptor,
I'm having a thought here, Barbossa.
What say we run up a flag of truce,
I scurry over to the Interceptor,
and I negotiate the return of your medallion?
Now, that's exactly the attitude that lost you the Pearl,
People are easy to search when they're dead.
Lock him in the brig.
Hands aloft to loose t'gallants!
With this wind, she'll carry every sail we've got!
What's happening?
The Black Pearl, She's gaining on us.
This is the fastest ship in the Caribbean.
You can tell them that after they've caught us.
We're shallower on the draft?
Aye.
Well, then can't we lose them amongst those shoals?
We don't have to outrun them long, just long enough.
Lighten the ship, stem to stern!
Anything we can afford to lose, see that it's lost.
Apparently, there's a leak.
Haul on the main brace! Make ready the guns!
And run out the sweeps.
-Pull! -Ho!
We're gonna need that.
It was a good plan.
Up till now.
Gibbs!
We have to make a stand.
We must fight!
Load the guns!
With what?
Anything. Everything!
Anything we have left.
Load the guns!
Case shot and langrage!
Nails and crushed glass!
With a will!
The Pearl's gonna luff up on our port quarter!
She'll rake us without ever presenting a target.
Lower the anchor on the right side.
On the starboard side!
It has the element of surprise.
You're daft, lady! You both are!
Daft like Jack!
Lower the starboard anchor!
Do it, you dogs, or it's you we'll load into the cannons!
Let go!
They're clubhauling!
Hard to port! Rack the starboard oars.
Hard to port!
Keep us steady, man.
Now!
Fire!
Fire all!
Stop blowing holes in my ship!
We could use a few more ideas, lass.
Your turn.
We need us a devil's dowry.
We'll give them her.
She's not what they're after.
The medallion.
Raise your colors, you bloomin' cockroaches!
Hands, grapnels, at the ready.
Prepare to board!
Blast all to carcasses, men!
Forward clear to the powder magazine.
And the rest of you, bring me that medallion!
Help!
Hey!
Below!
Thanks very much.
Jack!
Bloody empty.
Aaah!
That's not very nice.
Where's the medallion?
Wretch!
Ahh.
Where's dear William?
Will!
Elizabeth!
Monkey!
I can't move it!
Come on!
Will!
Elizabeth!
Why, thank you, Jack.
You're welcome.
Not you. We named the monkey "Jack."
Gents, our hope is restored!
Any of you so much as thinks the word "parley,"
I'll have your guts for garters.
Will!
You've got to stop it!
-Stop it! -Welcome back, miss.
You took advantage of our hospitality last time.
It holds fair now you return the favor.
Barbossa!
Will.
She goes free.
What's in your head, boy?
She goes free!
You've only got one shot, and we can't die.
Don't do anything stupid.
You can't.
I can.
Like that.
Who are you?
No one. He's no one.
A distant cousin of my aunt's nephew twice removed.
Lovely singing voice, though. Eunuch.
My name is Will Turner.
My father was Bootstrap Bill Turner.
His blood runs in my veins.
He's the spitting image of old Bootstrap Bill
come back to haunt us.
On my word, do as I say, or I'll pull this trigger
and be lost to Davy Jones' locker.
Name your terms, Mr. Turner.
Elizabeth goes free.
Yes, we know that one. Anything else?
And the crew. The crew are not to be harmed.
Agreed.
Go on, poppet, go!
Walk the plank!
Barbossa, you lying bastard! You swore she'd go free!
Don't dare impugn me honor, boy.
I agreed she'd go free,
but it was you who failed to specify when or where.
Though does seem a shame to lose something so fine, don't it?
Aye.
So I'll be having that dress back before you go.
I always liked you.
Goes with your black heart.
Ooh, it's still warm.
Off you go!
Come on!
Too long!
I'd really rather hoped we were past all this.
Jack...
Did you not notice?
That be the same island we made you governor of on our last little trip.
I did notice.
Perhaps you'll be able to conjure up
another miraculous escape.
But I doubt it.
Off you go.
Yeah.
Last time, you left me a pistol with one shot.
By the powers, you're right.
Where be Jack's pistol? Bring it forward.
Seeing as there's two of us, a gentleman would give us
a pair of pistols.
lt'll be one pistol as before,
You can be the gentleman and shoot the lady
and starve to death yourself.
That's the second time
I've had to watch that man sail away with my ship.
But you were marooned on this island before.
We can escape the same way you did.
To what point and purpose, young missy?
The Black Pearl is gone.
Unless you have a rudder and sails hidden in that bodice.
Unlikely.
Young Mr. Turner will be dead long before you can reach him.
But you're Captain Jack Sparrow.
You vanished from seven agents of the East lndia Company.
You sacked Nassau Port without even firing a shot.
Are you the pirate I've read about or not?
How did you escape last time?
Last time, I was here a grand total of three days, all right?
Last time...
The rumrunners used this island as a cache,
came by, and I was able to barter passage off.
From the looks of things,
they've long been out of business.
Probably have your bloody friend Norrington to thank for that.
So that's it, then?
That's the secret grand adventure
of the infamous Jack Sparrow?
You spent three days lying on a beach, drinking rum?
Welcome to the Caribbean, love.
BOTH:  We're devils, we're black sheep
We're really bad eggs
Drink up, me hearties, yo ho
Yo ho, yo ho
Ouch!
A pirate's life for me
I love this song!
Really bad eggs!
Ooh.
When I get the Pearl back,
I'm gonna teach it to the whole crew.
We'll sing it all the time.
You'll be the most fearsome pirate in the Spanish Main.
Not just the Spanish Main, love.
The entire ocean.
The entire world.
Wherever we want to go, we go. That's what a ship is, you know.
It's not just a keel and a deck and sails.
That's what a ship needs.
But what a ship is, what the Black Pearl really is,
is freedom.
Jack, it must be really terrible for you
to be trapped on this island.
Oh, yes.
But the company is infinitely better than last time,
I think.
The scenery has definitely improved.
-Mr. Sparrow. -Mm-hmm?
I'm not entirely sure I've had enough rum
to allow that kind of talk.
I know exactly what you mean, love.
To freedom.
To the Black Pearl,
No! Not good!
Stop! Not good!
What are you doing?
You burned all the food, the shade! The rum!
Yes, the rum is gone.
Why is the rum gone?
One, because it is a vile drink
that turns even the most respectable men into scoundrels.
Two, that signal is over a thousand feet high.
The entire Royal Navy is looking for me.
Do you think there is the slightest chance they won't see?
But why is the rum gone?
Just wait, Captain Sparrow.
You give it one hour, maybe two, and you will see
white sails on that horizon.
"Must've been terrible for you to be trapped here, Jack."
Well, it bloody is now!
There'll be no living with her after this.
-But we've got to save Will. -No.
You're safe now.
We will return to Port Royal,
not go gallivanting after pirates!
Then we condemn him to death.
The boy's fate is regrettable,
but so was his decision to engage in piracy.
To rescue me. To prevent anything from happening to me.
If I may be so bold as to inject my professional opinion.
The Pearl was listing near to scuppers after the battle.
It's very unlikely she'll be able to make good time.
Think about it.
The Black Pearl,
The last real pirate threat in the Caribbean, mate.
How can you pass that up, right?
By remembering that I serve others, Mr. Sparrow.
Not only myself.
Commodore, I beg you, please do this.
For me.
As a wedding gift.
Elizabeth.
Are you accepting the commodore's proposal?
I am.
A wedding! I love weddings!
Drinks all around!
I know.
"Clap him in irons," right?
Mr. Sparrow, you will accompany these fine men to the helm
and provide us with a bearing to lsla de Muerta.
You will spend the rest of the voyage
contemplating all meanings of the phrase
"silent as the grave."
Do I make myself clear?
lnescapably clear.
Shiver me timbers.
Cotton here says you missed a bit.
You knew William Turner?
Ol' Bootstrap Bill.
We knew him.
Never sat well with Bootstrap, what we did to Jack Sparrow.
The mutiny and all.
He said it wasn't right with the Code.
That's why he sent off a piece of the treasure to you.
He said we deserved to be cursed.
And remain cursed.
Stupid blighter.
Good man.
Well, as you can imagine,
that didn't sit too well with the captain.
That didn't sit too well with the captain at all.
-Tell him what Barbossa did. -I'm telling the story!
So, what the captain did.
He strapped a cannon to Bootstrap's bootstraps.
And last we saw of Ol' Bill Turner,
he was sinking to the crushing, black oblivion of Davy Jones' locker.
'Course it was only after that
we learned we needed his blood to lift the curse.
That's what you call ironic.
Bring him.
I don't care for the situation.
Any attempt to storm the caves could turn to an ambush.
Not if you're the one doing the ambushing.
I convince Barbossa to send his men out with their little boats.
You and your mates return to the Dauntless
and blast the bejesus out of them with your little cannons.
What do you have to lose?
Nothing I'd lament being rid of.
Now, to be quite honest with you,
there's a risk to those aboard the Dauntless,
which includes the future Mrs. Commodore.
Sorry, but it's for your own safety.
The commodore ordered! I have to tell him!
The pirates!
They're cursed! They can't be killed!
Don't worry. He's informed of that.
A mermaid flopped up on deck and told him the whole story.
This is Jack Sparrow's doing!
No reason to fret.
Just a prick of the finger. A few drops of blood.
No mistakes this time.
He's only half Turner. We spill it all!
Guess there is reason to fret.
Beg your pardon. Beg your pardon.
-Begun by blood. -Excuse me.
By blood --
Jack!
It's not possible.
Not probable.
Where's Elizabeth?
She's safe, just like I promised.
She's set to marry Norrington, like she promised.
You get to die for her, like you promised.
So we're all men of our word, really.
Except for Elizabeth who is, in fact, a woman.
Shut up! You're next.
You don't want to be doing that, mate.
No, I really think I do.
Your funeral.
Why don't I want to be doing it?
Well, because...
Because the HMS Dauntless, pride of the Royal Navy,
is floating just offshore, waiting for you.
What we doing here?
The pirates come out, unprepared and unawares.
We catch them in a crossfire, send them down to see Old Hob.
I know why we're here.
I meant, why aren't we doing
what Mr. Sparrow said we should do with the cannons and all?
Because it was Mr. Sparrow who said it.
You think he wasn't telling the truth?
Just hear me out, mate.
You order your men to row to the Dauntless,
They do what they do best.
Robert's your uncle. Fannie's your aunt.
There you are with two ships.
The makings of your very own fleet.
You'll take the grandest as your flagship, and who's to argue?
But what of the Pearl?
Name me captain.
I'll sail under your colors. I'll give you 10% of me plunder.
And you get to introduce yourself as Commodore Barbossa.
Savvy?
I suppose in exchange, you want me not to kill the whelp.
No, no, no. Not at all. By all means, kill the whelp.
Just not yet.
Wait to lift the curse until the opportune moment.
For instance...
After you've killed Norrington's men.
Every last one.
You've been planning this from the beginning.
Ever since you learned my name.
Yeah.
I want 50% of your plunder.
-15%.  -40%.
25%\n25%.
I'll buy you the hat.
A really big one, Commodore.
We have an accord.
All hands to the boats!
Apologies.
You give the orders.
Gents, take a walk.
Not to the boats?
Hold fire.
Oh, this is just like what the Greeks done at Troy.
Except they was in a horse instead of dresses.
Wooden horse.
A moment, please.
Elizabeth?
I just want you to know
I believe you made a very good decision today.
Couldn't be more proud of you.
But, you know, even a good decision,
if made for the wrong reasons, can be a wrong decision.
Look into that. Report back.
Lieutenant?
Yoo-hoo!
Elizabeth?
Are you there?
Elizabeth, are you even listening to me?
Oh, what have you done?
-Oooh! -Stop that!
Already feel like a fool.
Look nice, though.
I look nice?
I must admit, Jack, I thought I had you figured.
But it turns out you're a hard man to predict.
Me? I'm dishonest.
And a dishonest man you can always trust to be dishonest.
Honestly.
It's the honest ones you want to watch for,
because you can never predict
when they're going to do something incredibly stupid.
Aaah!
You're off the edge of the map, mate.
Here there be monsters.
Right!Right!
What would you pick to eat first?
I think we should decide now.
Just so we're ready when the time comes.
What was that?
Shh!
Miss Elizabeth!
Make for the ship! Move!
To the ship!
Row, men!
You can't beat me, Jack.
That's interesting.
I couldn't resist, mate.
Aaah!
Sorry!
So what now, Jack Sparrow?
Are we to be two immortals locked in an epic battle
until judgment day and trumpets sound?
Or you could surrender.
Aaaah!
All of you with me!
Will is in that cave. We must save him.
Ready. And heave!
Please, I need your help! Come on!
Any port in a storm.
Cotton's right. We've got the Pearl,
What about Jack? Are you gonna leave him?
Jack owes us a ship.
There's the Code to consider.
The Code?
You're pirates.
Hang the Code, and hang the rules!
They're more like guidelines anyway.
Bloody pirates!
-Hey. -What?
Is it supposed to be doing that?
They're stealing our ship!
Bloody pirates!
Boarders, away!
Come on!
Gaaah!
Me eye!
-Aaaah! -Aaaah!
I'm gonna teach you the meaning of pain!
Do you like pain?
Try wearing a corset.
Whose side is Jack on?
At the moment?
Aaaaaah!
No fair.
Ten years you carry that pistol, and now you waste your shot.
He didn't waste it.
I feel...
Cold.
Parley?
The ship is ours, gentlemen.
Huzzah!
We should return to the Dauntless,
Your fiance will be wanting to know you're safe.
If you were waiting for the opportune moment...
That was it.
If you'd be so kind,
I'd be much obliged if you'd drop me off at my ship.
I'm sorry, Jack.
They done what's right by them. Can't expect more than that.
"Jack Sparrow, be it known that you..."
Captain. Captain Jack Sparrow.
"For your willful commission of crimes against the crown."
"Said crimes being numerous in quantity
and sinister in nature.
The most egregious of these to be cited herewith.
Piracy, smuggling..."
This is wrong.
Commodore Norrington is bound by the law.
As are we all.
"lmpersonating an officer of the Spanish Royal Navy.
lmpersonating a cleric of the church of England."
Ah, yeah.
"Sailing under false colors, arson, kidnapping,
looting, poaching, brigandage, pilfering, depravity,
depredation, and general lawlessness.
And for these crimes
you have been sentenced to be, on this day,
hung by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy on your soul."
Governor Swann.
Commodore.
Elizabeth.
I should have told you every day from the moment I met you.
I love you.
Marines.
I can't breathe.
Elizabeth!
Move!
What...
Come on!
-Right! -Come on, lads!
I thought we might endure some ill-conceived escape attempt.
But not from you.
On our return to Port Royal, I granted you clemency.
And this is how you thank me?
By throwing in your lot with him?
He's a pirate!
And a good man.
If all I have achieved is the hangman
will earn two pairs of boots instead of one, so be it.
My conscience will be clear.
You forget your place, Turner.
It's right here between you and Jack.
As is mine.
Elizabeth!
Lower your weapons.
For goodness sake, put them down!
So this is where your heart truly lies, then?
It is.
Well! I'm actually feeling rather good about this.
I think we've all arrived at a special place.
Spiritually.
Ecumenically.
Grammatically.
I want you to know that I was rooting for you, mate.
Know that.
Elizabeth.
It would never have worked between us, darling.
I'm sorry.
Will.
Nice hat.
Friends.
This is a day that you will always remember
as the day that...
ldiot. He has nowhere to go but back to the noose.
Sail ho!
What's your plan of action?
Sir?
Perhaps on the rare occasion
pursuing the right course demands an act of piracy,
piracy itself can be the right course?
Mr. Turner.
I will accept the consequences of my actions.
This is a beautiful sword.
I would expect the man who made it to show the same care
in every aspect of his life.
Thank you.
Commodore!
What about Sparrow?
Well, I think we can afford to give him one day's head start.
So.
This is the path you've chosen, is it?
After all, he is a blacksmith.
No.
He's a pirate.
Heave!
Thought you were supposed to keep to the Code.
We figured they were more actual guidelines.
Thank you.
Captain Sparrow.
The Black Pearl is yours.
On deck, you scabrous dogs!
Hands to braces!
Let down and haul to run free!
Now, bring me that horizon.
And really bad eggs.
Drink up, me hearties, yo ho!